## David O<u>kolie</u>

Entry Level Software Engineer

#### Contact

**Address** 

Lagos, 100231

**Phone** 

07030783132

E-mail

okoliedave1@gmail.com

**Twitter** 

https://twitter.com/David\_Inkheart

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-okolie-762780a1/

www

https://zety.com/profile/davi d-okolie/218

#### Skills

Architecture and design

Very Good

Strong verbal and written communicator

Very Good

**Technical Writing** 

Very Good

Debugging

Average

Algorithms and data structures

Highly motivated budding Software Engineer who is on a challenging but amazing journey into the world of technologies. Currently enrolled in an immersive program that engages technology enthusiasts and budding software engineers in various programs across in-demand tech disciplines to prepare them for a global career as a Full-Stack Developer. Has excellent problemsolving skills, and ability to perform well in a team. Years of hands-on experience in Architectural Design and Construction has imparted technical and managerial skills needed in the life cycle of a design, project or product.

#### **Education**

2022-06 -Current

## Certification of Skill and Proficiency: Software Engineering

Alx-Holberton School of Software Engineering - Online, Africa

Completed course work and projects in;

- Low-level programming & Algorithm Hatching out,
- Low-level programming & Algorithm Data structures and Algorithms
- Low-level programming & Algorithm Linux and Unix system programming
- System engineering & DevOps Bash
- Technical Writing and Networking Social media
  Continuing education in;
- Technical Writing, Recursion, Whiteboarding, Object-oriented programming, Test Driven Development, Error Handling and I/O, Web Scraping, Databases, Systems Engineering/Devops, Regexes.

2020-06 -2021-03

# BCS Level 4 Certificate in IT.: Information Technology

BCS, The Chartered Institute for IT. - Swindon, SN1 1BY, UK

Completed course work in Information Systems,
 Computer Network Technology and Software
 Development.

2009-10 -2014-02

### **Bachelor of Science: Architecture**

University of Nigeria - Enugu, Nigeria.

Very Good Systems Engineering Average Source code review Good HTML and CSS proficiency Basic Software Development Average **Cultural Awareness** Very Good Python Average

Planning and Coordination

Very Good

C (Programming Language)

Good

2016-04

Object Oriented Programming

Basic

Linux/Unix, CLI and Shell proficiency

Good

Project Management

Very Good

**Javascript** 

Basic

## **Work History**

Freelance Architect and Builder 2021-08 -Current Self, Lagos • Created, printed and modified drawings in AutoCAD and Revit. Consulted with clients to determine functional and spatial requirements of new structure. • Researched materials to determine appropriate selection for projects. Verified construction documentation to meet client requirements and vision. **Project Team Lead** 2021-01 -2021-08 PHLEXCOM NIG. LTD., Lagos 2019-01 -**Architect/Project Manager** 2020-12 Adisa Design Studio, Lagos 2017-02 -**Project Architect** 2019-01 Flojonnie Nigeria Limited, Lagos 2016-04 -**Resident Architect** 2016-09 Design-Age Consults, Lagos 2014-05 -**Graduate Architect** 

## Reading and playing video games

Agram Nig. Ltd, Lagos

I like reading Science Fiction and Fantasy, and Nonfiction on Science, Technology, Culture and Philosophy.

I mostly play Soccer and Arcade Video games.